Hi guys, this is Andrew Vagotsski and
Brit Contrera has asked me to film a
short video explaining how to find the
hip extension moment in the hip thrust.
And it's not as simple as it seems
because
uh I'll start first uh with an example
of the squat. So typically people think
okay there's the barbell if you draw the
force vector. Sorry about that.
Um anyway, if you draw the force vector
going down, which would be that line,
then the moment arm to the hip would be
that. The moment arm to the knee would
be that. And while that's true, it
ignores uh all of the body weight. Um so
that's problematic. So a better way to
look at it is if we look at the force
vector coming
up, but then it becomes less accurate as
we go up. So, it's full of problems and
it's not necessarily the most accurate,
but it does allow for
a I don't a good fast estimate as
opposed to breaking down each segment
individually and looking at the moments.
So, we're going to use something that's
based on that type of idea for the hip
thrust. But how we're going to do it is
a little bit different because the hip
thrust is a much more complicated
exercise and you'll see in why in a
minute. If we have a load right here on
top of the
hips and the force vector from that load
is going to go
down. Now, one proposed way of looking
at it is if we draw the hips over here,
there's the
femur, there's the
torso, and there's the
load. And it's not a perfect drawing, I
know, but you get the point. Let's say
the load is just off center from the
hips. That would mean the moment arm is
tiny.
And that's what some people say. But if
you look at how this load acts, this
load would act to extend the hip, which
means that your hip flexors would have
to be used in order to flex the hip or
resist that extension, which doesn't
make sense. That means the load would do
all the work going up. And for what the
hip thrust is, that's that's not a good
model. So we have to look at it another
way.
In the hip thrust, there are two points
of contact. There's uh where the back
touches the bench right here, and
there's where the foot touches the
floor. So, if we were to put a force
plate right where the foot is,
uh you're going to see a force vector
coming out of the foot. Now, it won't
just be vertical, but there will also be
a horizontal force vector. And this is
because your knees act or your hip
extensors actively try to extend the
knee which is going to try to basically
force your shank that
way. But because you're on the ground,
it the ground is going to try to resist
that and that's going to create a force
vector that way. So you're then going to
get a force vector that's like
that that's somewhat diagonal.
And because this won't account for all
of your body's weight plus the load of
that, there's also going to be a force
vector coming out of the bench. And it's
going to have to be equal and opposite.
The horizontal is going to have to be
equal and opposite to
this. So you have that. And then the
vertical is going to have to be the
difference between
uh the magnitude of this and the sum of
the load plus the body weight. So we're
going to have that coming up.
So that's going to produce another force
vector like that. Now, if we were to
extend these force vectors
out, bear with my terrible
drawing, then you're going to have to
draw the moment arms from the hip
joint out to the position of the load
vector or the ground reaction
force. And
also and these lines basically represent
the moment arms which are the
perpendicular distance from the line of
action. So that would be the reaction
force at the bench and the reaction
force at the
floor and those would be the moment
arms. Then we would
take so that's the moment arm from the
bench and this is the force from the
bench.
Then we have the moment arm from the
floor and then we have the force from
the floor. So then in order to find the
moment at the
hip and we're going to do the absolute
value of
it, it's going to be equal
to the force from the bench times the
moment arm from the bench plus the force
from the
floor times the moment
arm from the floor.
And that's a very oversimplified way to
look at how to find the hip extension
moment and the hip thrust. Now, there's
a much more complicated way and we're
going to try to come out with a model of
this later this year, but until then,
you guys can look at it like this.
Thanks. Hope this helped.